Subramanya V Maiya

Data Analyst| +91 7204848776

subramanyamaiya07@gmail.com |

Summary

A Certified Data Analyst and a software developer with 3.8 years of total experience executing datadriven solutions in the field of healthcare and life science domain and with an ability to adapt, improvise and overcome challenges across different work domains.

SKILLS

< Machine Learning: Classification, Regression, Unsupervised Learning

<Statistical Methods: Predictive Analysis, Hypothesis testing, A/B Testing

<Programming Languages: Python, C#, Javascript, php | Big Data Language: Spark</pre>

AWS: S3, Redshift, DynamoDB, Step Function, AWS Glue, IAM roles, EMR, Cognito

< Database Language: SQL

< Data Reporting Tool: Tableau, Power BI

<MS Office: Word, Excel, PowerPoint

EXPERIENCE

Indegene, Bangalore – (Data Analyst)

January 2020 - PRESENT

- **Common Data Model:** Created a common data model pipeline, which helps to transform and store the data from different sources in a common table.
- **Network Graphs:** Involved in creation of graph-theory based Single and Multi-Layer Network graph tool enabling the user to visualize and comprehend interrelation between the disease, procedure and drugs for a given therapeutic area.
- **Cohort Builder:** Dashboard for the user to create the cohort based on his interests which can be used for further analysis.
- Patient Stratification using DBSCAN: Identification of high-risk patients from a given therapeutic area using variables associated to the medical history, comorbidities, demographics, medication-adherence
- **Data Wrangling and Exception Handling:** Routine cleansing, maintenance and transformation of Medical Claims data
- **Feature Engineering:** Actively involved in the process of feature engineering and feature selection supervised under the expertise of the domain team

Fortunesoft IT Innovations, Bangalore – (Software Engineer)

Aug 2017 - June 2019

Collegewear and Pearson Words their Way Digital

- Gathering of requirements from the client and documenting it.
- Designing of databases based on the requirements.
- Creating backend for both the web applications and also API's which can be used in mobile application.
- Application debugging and query optimization for optimal database performance.
- Backend code optimization and code enhancements.

Prime Focus Technology, Bangalore – (Junior Software Engineer Intern)

Aug 2017 - June 2019

CLEAR Tenant Automation

Tool for onboarding tenant in CLEAR. Manual configuration of tenant was replaced by automation. Automation brought time to deploy tenant from week to hour

- Analysis of the system functionality with respect to change requests and developing the new request on the given time.
- Bug detection and Fixing.

CERTIFICATIONS

• Post Graduate Program in Data Science and Engineering (PGP-DSE) | Great Lakes | 2019

EDUCATION

Course	Institution	Year	Remark s
Post graduate program in Data Science Engineering	Great Lakes Institute of Management	2019	Completed
BE/B. Tech	VidyaVardhaka College of Engineering	2016	70.17%
12 th Std	MASVS Gurukula	2012	84.2%
10 th Std	Daisy Convent	2010	83.2%

OTHER ACHEIVEMENTS

- Secured 4th place in district level open chess tournament held at Basudev Somani College, Mysuru
- Represented college in VTU(Visvesvaraya Technological University) shuttle badminton at zonal level in the year 2014.